







SCJP, SCWCD Technical Manager seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution

Architecture, Java, SQL, PL/SQL, PIG, Hive, Angular, Spring, Hibernate, Restful Services

Current Designation: Technical Manager - Java Total Experience: 14 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Capgemini Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MS/MSc(Science) [Computer

Science] Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Role: Project Mar-IT/Software

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Technical Manager, Project Manager-IT/Software Development, Application Programming, Application

Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Java, SQL, PL/SQL, PIG, Hive, Angular, Spring, Hibernate, Restful Services

Verified : Le Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Gururaja Kalmanje is a Technical Manager with 14+ years of demonstrated experience in the information technology & services industry. Certified Professional with AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate besides several other certifications which include Java Certified (SCJP (Sun Certified Java Programmer), SCWCD (Sun Certified Web Component Developer), & SCDJWS (Sun Certified Developer for Java Web Services)

Work Experience

Capgemini as Technical Manager -Java Jun 2014 to Till Date

Project Duration (From & To in Month/Year Format) September 2016 - Till Date

Role/Title Technical Manager Work Location Bangalore, India

Project Description

Strategic Functionality (SF) & Guest Account Management (GAM) is a project which has been migrated from a monolithic based architecture (SF) to Mcroservice based architecture (GAM). The primary objective of this system is to provide single view of the Guest & Guest experiences for both WaltDisneyWorld (WDW) & Disneyland Resorts (DLR) theme parks. In addition to storing and managing data, GAMwill be the "glue" that links this NGE (Next Generation Experience) specific data to WDWs existing sources of data.

Responsibilities

Accountable in delivering the deliverables from offshore perspective by closely working with Offshore Leads and communicating with all internal & external stakeholders.

Responsible in preparing /reviewing the design artifacts with all the stakeholders and coming up with the initial framework/ guidelines for the development team to follow.

Responsible in monitoring of the production systems post release & analyzing the RCA for any blocking production issues using tools like App Dynamics & Splunk.

Mentoring/Leading team in completing the user stories as per the sprint schedules and proactively resolve any impediments by coordinating with different team members/stakeholders.

Conducting brown bag sessions with external teams to exchange knowledge on various technical implementations specifically on AWS cloud within our project.

Reviewing the Weekly and Monthly status reports with the customers.

Training new team members and taking more ownership on junior resources and ensuring them to be billable within short time.

AWS Cloud Platform Hardware

Languages / Middleware Java / J2EE, Spring Boot, RabbitMQ, SQL

Organization Name Capgemini

Project Name Itools

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Project Duration (From & To in Month/Year Format) June 2014 - September 2016

Role/Title Technical Lead Work Location Bangalore, India

Project Description

ITools is an internal project for Societe Generale comprise of several in house built applications like invoicing system (aka BMS system), Roaster management system (RMS), Attendance Management system (AMS) etc., and also an application called EWhiteboard (Digital Scrum board) which are used by internal SGGSC employees and is a Maintenance/Enhancement kind of engagement.

Responsibilities Performed Functional Role (BA) by gathering the business requirements from the Finance users and other stake holders in the implementation of an in-house invoicing tool for the customer.

Responsible in converting the business requirements into Technical Specifications and making team to understand the end user requirements and implement the technical components according to the user requirements by following proper design and coding practices.

Responsible in preparing the UAT test cases for the invoicing tool and coordination with the end users during UAT phase across several releases and coordinating with the team in resolving the technical issues within the release timelines

Performed Functional / Technical Lead Role for an application called EWhiteboard (Digital Scrum Board) which is designed & developed on Angular & Spring Framework.

Responsible in the development of key modules of EWhiteboard application which also includes a real time update using Web Sockets.

As a Technical Lead responsible in the development & maintenance of several other in house tools like Roaster management (Employee Shift Management Tool), Attendance Management Tool (AWS), Billing Management System (BMS - Invoicing Tool) etc..

Responsible in preparing the estimations using PERT estimation technique and assigning / tracking the progress of tasks in JIRA by following Agile methodology.

Cognizant as Technical Lead

Apr 2011 to Jun 2014

Work Location Hyderabad, India

performing the Air/Car/Hotel booking for the American Express card members. This application is to decommission the existing systems (Saturn / Smartrez) which is being used currently by the Amex travel agents for performing the bookings for the American Express card members.

Responsible in preparation of build plan and the delivery of the user stories for each sprint.

Responsible in getting the clarifications for the user stories from the BSA's and the business on priority and make the development team understand the requirement and complete the user stories within the sprint timelines

Responsible in performing the code reviews and code-quality checks and making the team to incorporate them within the sprint timelines to ensure the user stories are delivered with quality.

Responsible in owning and monitoring the defects in QC for Integration and regression testing and ensuring the defects are resolved by coordinating/ supporting the development team.

Mentoring and supporting the team members in resolving the technical issues.

Operating Systems Linux

Software / Special Tools BMDB2 v8.0, IBMWeb Sphere Application Server, Memcached. Languages Java 1.5, Web Services (JAX-WS), JSP

Frameworks Spring, Hibernate

Organization Name Cognizant

Project Name SQL Migration (Jrun - Jboss / SQL Server 2005 - 2008 Migration) Project Duration (From & To in Month/Year Format) April/2012 - May/2013

Role/Title Technical Lead Work Location Hyderabad, India

Project Description Mgration of product (Recognition / Sales) owned by Maritz (client) from Jrun to JBoss and SQL Server 2005 to SQL Server 2008 which is being used by nearly 35 clients of Maritz

This is a migration project for a product of Maritz which is been used by several clients. In this migration each client using this product is been migrated from the current Jrun platform to JBoss5.1 platform and SQL Server 2005 to SQL Server 2008.

As part of this migration there are few clients to whom the product also need to be upgraded from their existing version to the current product version (12.5).

Responsibilities

Responsible in migrating the clients from Jrun to Jboss server

Responsible in upgrading the client product versions from their current version to latest 12.5 version.

Responsible in deploying and unit testing the migrated clients on Development Servers

Responsible in supporting the UAT before moving the migrated clients to Production.

Mentoring and supporting the junior team members in resolving the technical complexities.

Operating Systems Linux Software / Special Tools JRun , JBoss, SQL Server 2008 Languages Java 1.5, JSP, SQL

Frameworks Spring

Organization Name Cognizant

Project Name MApply Blue Upgrade and Tracking Tags

Project Duration (From & To in Month/Year Format) August/2011 - March/2012

Role/Title Sr. Java Programmer Work Location Hyderabad, India

Project Description Mapply is the AMEX (American Express) mobile application for applying for the new cards or for upgrading the existing cards for the existing card members. This application has two major modules namely

Prospects and

Upgrade

AWEX Cards are classified into CCSG (Personal Cards) or OPEN (Business Cards). Prospects module mainly deals with applying for a new card application and Upgrade deals with upgrading the existing user's card if eligible

Tracking Tags is the functionality implemented in the Prospects module to track the pages users mostly visit in the MApply application.

There are 4 types of tracking tags which dynamically gets generated in different jsp's.

Meta-tags Non-decision tags Decision tags Marin tags

Responsibilities

Responsible in the implementation of the Non-Decision, Decision & Marin tags.

Responsible in the implementation of Tracking Tags Parser

IBM India Pvt Ltd as Sr. Java Programmer

May 2007 to Aug 2011

Project Duration (From & To in Month/Year Format) October / 2010 - August / 2011

Role/Title Sr. Java Programmer Work Location Hyderabad, India

Project Description ICD 10 Crosswalk Intelligent Framework (ICIF) project is an healthcare asset developed for health care payers which provides an ability to convert code from ICD-9-CM to ICD-10-CM and PCS

and vice versa for processing the health care claims. Basically these are the clinical codes which will be used by the EDI engines along with other information to process the health care daims

Mapping from ICD-10-CM and PCS codes back to ICD-9-CM codes is referred to as backward mapping. Mapping from ICD-9-CM codes to ICD-10-CM and PCS codes is referred to

as forward mapping. The (General Equivalence Mapping) GEMs are a comprehensive translation dictionary that can be used to accurately and effectively translate any ICD-9-CM-based data. ICIF application will make use of these GEM files to convert the data from one coding system to other.

Responsibilities

Responsible in the implementation of the service layer using spring and data access layer using JPA with Open JPA implementation for ICIF model office module.

Responsible in the end to end implementation of the Web Service for ICIF runtime services module.

Responsible in generating and configuring the JPA entities from the database tables for entire ICIF model office

Involved in the business requirement meetings along with team lead and architect with the business users and Business Analysts during requirement phase and coming up with the Schema structure for input / output for the runtime

Responsible in analyzing and updating the schema and wsdl changes for the runtime services.

Responsible in unit testing using Junit.

Operating Systems Linux

Software / Special Tools IBM DB2 v8.0, Apache Tomcat Server Languages Java 1.5, Web Services (JAX-WS), JSP

Frameworks Struts 1.2, Open JPA

Organization Name IBM India Pvt Ltd

Project Name Enterprise Customer Information File (ECIF)

Project Duration (From & To in Month/Year Format) January/2010 - October / 2010

Role/Title Sr. Java Programmer Work Location Hyderabad, India

Project Description The Enterprise Customer Information File (ECIF) project will provide a consolidated enterprise wide 360-degree view of Customer Information across product lines and business units. The project maintains the common data store of Nationwide Insurance Customer Information using the IBM Master Data Management MDM) product. (earlier called as IBMWebsphere Customer Center (WCC)).

Customer Information Service Provider (CISP) is one of the components within the ECIF. It provides a layer of decoupling between the Nationwide Enterprise layer and the MDMlayer. CISP is the primary endpoint for customer related information services. ie., it provides the entry point for all Online Services for ECIF.

The Services Offered by CISP mainly include search for Customer Information / Agreement Summary, Retrieving Customer Information / Agreement Summary and maintaining Customer Profile and Preferences.

The high level Operational activities performed by CISP are:

- 1. Request data cleansing services.
- 2. Request customer information search, retrieval, and update.
- 3. Receive customer information responses.
- 4. Transform customer information requests / responses from IAAXML to MDMXML and back.
- 5. Log access and errors and returns error information to requestor.

Responsibilities

Responsible in creating the Service Design & Service Specification documents from the Functional Specification Documents (FSD) for each release. (one release for every 3 months.)

Responsible in analyzing and updating the schema changes for the services in each release.

Responsible in the end to end implementation of the Web Services according to the release requirements and unit testing using JUNIT.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computer Science) from Osmania University in 2001

PG: MS/M.Sc(Science) (Computer Science) from Osmania University in 2004

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience

LINUX
Oracle 11g, Jenkins, Sonar
Java 1.7, SQL, PL/SQL
Spring M/C, Hibernate
Angular JS, JSP, JQuery
Hibernate 4.0, Open JPA
Struts 1.2, Restful Services
MICRO SERVICES
Splunk & AppDynamics
Aws services
Jenkins, SONAR, Rabbit MQ
Maven, GIT, IBM MDM

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.